jacksonsart.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy | Jackson's Art Supplies

This policy outlines how we obtain, store, use and share your personal information

 **What Does This Policy Cover?**

  1. Our Commitment To Your Privacy
  2. Relevant Legislation
  3. Our Privacy Policy Principles
  4. Who Are We?
  5. What Information Do We Collect About You and Where Do We Store it??
  6. How Do We Use The Information We Collect About You?
  7. The Legal Basis For Processing Personal Data
  8. Data Breaches
  9. Cookies
  10. Our Third-Party Data Processors
  11. Data Controller
  12. Our Commitment to Data Security
  13. Our Commitment to Children's Privacy
  14. How You Can Access Your Information?
  15. How To Contact Us
  16. Data Retention
  17. Your Rights
  18. Changes to Our Privacy Policy

 **1.        ****Our Commitment To Your Privacy**

Your privacy is important to us and we are committed to protecting your personal information. To better protect your privacy, we provide this policy explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

 **2.        ****Relevant Legislation:**

Along with our business and internal computer systems, this website is designed to comply with the following national and international legislation with regards to data protection and user privacy:

 **3.        ****Our Privacy Policy Principles**

  * You may opt in or out of our email communications at any time
  * You have the right to remove any information we may hold on you
  * We will never sell, rent, make public or distribute your personal information
  * Data is a liability and therefore should only be collected and processed when absolutely necessary

 **4.        ****Who Are We?**

  * We are Jackson’s Art Supplies Limited.
  * Our Company Registration Number is 3913002
  * Our Registered Office is at 1 Farleigh Place, London, N16 7SX.
  * Our Data Protection Officer (DPO) is Stuart Small, Operations Director
  * Our Data Protection Officer, Stuart Small, can be contacted at Jackson’s Art Supplies, Unit J, Edison Close, Waterwells Business Park, Quedgeley, Gloucester, GL2 2FN or 01452 228482 or [stuart@jacksonsart.co.uk](mailto:stuart@jacksonsart.co.uk)

This policy explains our role as a data controller when we use your personal information in order to fulfil the orders you place with us or interact with us through our website.

 **5.        ****What Information Do We Collect About You** **And Where Do We Store It?**

This Policy applies to all information we collect or is voluntarily submitted on the Jackson’s Art website. This website collects and uses personal information for the following reasons:

 **Online Forms**

We collect the personal information you voluntarily provide to us, which includes your name and e-mail address, in order to subscribe to our newsletter, receive our free content, comment on our blog, and/or purchase services or online products. 

 **Customer Data**

If you make an online purchase of our products and/or services, subscribe to our newsletter, comment on our blog, make requests or leave feedback then we will collect the following  information;

  * Name
  * Address (billing and Delivery)
  * Email address
  * Contact Phone number
  * Delivery Instructions

This information is held securely on our servers.

 **Website Visitor Tracking**

Like most websites, our website uses Google Analytics. This tool collects information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. We use this information to better understand how visitors find us and how they interact with our website. We can use this to make adjustments to our website, to deliver a better user experience.  

We also use tracking from Facebook and Pinterest so that we can better understand how visitors are interacting with our site via social media and to track the effectiveness of any adverts we place on social media.

This data is all anonymised but you can opt out of this tracking at any time via your own browser settings. See our [Cookie Policy](https://www.jacksonsart.com/cookie-policy) for more details.

Our website uses software that tracks your IP data. This information is supplied to us from

When you visit our site, we may automatically log your IP address, a unique identifier for your computer or other access device. We will not use your IP address to identify you, the individual, in any way

We use IP addresses for the purpose of the restoring of basket information or changing the language of currency.

 **Contact Forms and Email Links**

Should you choose to contact us using the contact form on our Contact Us Page, none of the data that you supply will be stored by this website or passed to / be processed by any of the third-party data processors defined in section below.  Instead the data will be collated into an email and sent to us over the Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP). Our SMTP servers are protected by TLS (sometimes known as SSL) meaning that the email content is encrypted using SHA-2, 256-bit cryptography before being sent across the internet. The email content is then decrypted by our local computers and devices.

We store information on our own secure servers

 **6.        ****How Do We Use The Information We Collect About You?**

We collect information about you to understand your needs and provide you with a better service. Specifically, we use your information for:

  * Internal record keeping
  * Improving our services

The legal basis for this type of processing is either consent or our legitimate interests in growing our business.

Providing you with offers relating to our products or services. 

  * The legal basis for this type of processing is either consent or our legitimate interests in growing our business.

We may send you such communications if you requested it and/or if you agreed to receive such communications. You can opt-out of these emails at any time through the ‘unsubscribe’ button in each email or contacting us via email.

We will only share your information with trusted 3rd parties if necessary to provide support in running this Website. We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.

We use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order only to complete that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order.

We use the information you provide about someone else when placing an order only to ship the product and to confirm delivery. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to complete that order.

We use return email addresses to answer the email we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties. We undertake not to retain any of your personally identifiable data any longer than necessary. Data will be retained for the purposes already mentioned in this policy until such time as it becomes no longer valid or you specifically request its removal.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing you an opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. We will always provide you with a simple way to later opt out later should you change your mind.

We never transfer any of your personally identifiable information outside of the EU.

 **Google Analytics**

Like most websites, this site uses Google Analytics (GA) to track user interaction. We use this data to determine the number of people using our site, to better understand how they find and use our web pages and to see their journey through the website.

Although GA records data such as your geographical location, device, internet browser and operating system, none of this information personally identifies you to us. GA also records your computer’s IP address which could be used to personally identify you but Google do not grant us access to this. We consider Google to be a third-party data processor (see Third Part Processors below).

GA makes use of cookies, details of which can be found on [Google’s developer guides](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage). Disabling cookies on your internet browser will stop GA from tracking any part of your visit to pages within this website.

To collect feedback via Feefo (more information below)

 **Feefo**

We currently employ an independent review company called Feefo to email customers on our behalf, asking for feedback on both service and the products they have purchased. This is to help us improve customer satisfaction.

 **How Does It Work?**

Once you place your order with us, Feefo will send you an email, requesting feedback on the products and service you have received from Jackson's Art Supplies. Feefo will not contact you for any other reason. Their role within Jackson's Art Supplies' organisation is one of Data Processor, and as such they have no control over your contact details. Feefo are employed by Jackson's Art Supplies (the Data Controller) to use your contact details solely for the purpose of requesting feedback. Your feedback will appear on the Jackson's Art Supplies section of Feefo.com as well as on Jacksonsart.com (as part of the product information for the product that you have reviewed). All feedback remains anonymous online, although Jackson's staff are able to access your contact details so that they can respond to feedback where necessary.

 **How Can They Be Trusted With My Data?**

Feefo are not a third party and have no ownership over the information passed to them. The data remains 100% secure. Feefo work with a large number of highly reputable online stores and have consistently proven to help online stores, including Jackson's Art Supplies, raise their online presence as well as inform customers of the real standard of service and products supplied, as reported by fellow customers with a 100% impartial opinion.

There is no obligation to provide feedback - each email that Feefo send will invite you to opt out should you wish to.

You can also email us at customerservices@jacksonsart.co.uk and we can also instruct Feefo to stop contacting you.

 **Third Party Data Disclosure**

The Information Commissioner's Office states that:

Third party, in relation to personal data, means any person other than –

(a) the data subject,

(b) the data controller, or

(c) any data processor or other person authorised to process data for the data controller or processor

Jackson's Art Supplies will never give any customer data to any third party.

You should be aware that if we are requested by the police or any other regulatory or government authority investigating suspected illegal activities to provide your personal information and/or user information, we are entitled to do so.

 **7.        ****The Legal Basis For Processing Personal Data**

These are the following legal reasons for processing personal data:

  * For the performance of a contract with you.

  * Internal record keeping for statutory purposes.
  * For the legitimate interests in growing our business.

  * For the purpose of furthering Jackson’s legitimate interests including providing better products and services.

  * For marketing purposes where you opted in to receive marketing communications from us. We will process your personal data and provide you with marketing communications in line with the preferences you have provided

 **8.        ****Data Breaches:**

We will report any unlawful data breach of this website’s database or the database(s) of any of our third-party data processors to any and all relevant persons and authorities within 72 hours of the breach if it is apparent that personal data stored in an identifiable manner has been stolen.

 **9.        ****Cookies:**

A cookie is a piece of code that allows the web server to identify and track activity of the web browser. They are widely used in order to make websites work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the website.

You can enable or disable your Cookie settings via your own web browser. See our Cookies Policy for more details.

For further details please consult the help menu in your browser or visit www.allaboutcookies.org

Cookies may be used to keep track of the contents of your shopping cart for example. You can turn off cookies within your browser by going to 'Tools | Internet Options | Privacy' and selecting to block cookies. If you turn off cookies, you will be unable to place orders or benefit from the other features that use cookies such as logging on or creating an account.

 **10.    ****Our Third-Party Data Processors:**

We use a number of third parties to process personal data on our behalf. These third parties have been carefully chosen and all of them comply with the legislation set out in the Privacy Policy.

  * Google ([Privacy policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en-GB/policies/privacy/))
  * Dotmailer (Privacy Policy)
  * Royal Mail ([Privacy Policy](https://www.parcelforce.com/privacy?utm_source=emailmarketing&utm_medium=email&utm_campaign=ac2208_gdpr_customer_comms_11052018&utm_content=2018-05-24))
  * Whistle ([Privacy Policy](https://www.whistl.co.uk/privacy/))
  * Direct Link ([Privacy Policy](https://www.directlink.com/about-us/privacy-policy/))
  * DPD ([Privacy Policy](https://www.dpd.co.uk/privacy_policy.jsp))
  * DHL / Deutsche Post ([Privacy Policy](http://www.dpdhl.com/en/data_protection.html))
  * APC ([Privacy Policy](https://www.apc-direct.co.uk/content/privacy-policy))
  * Parcel Force ([Privacy Policy](https://www.parcelforce.com/privacy))
  * Freight Route ([Privacy Policy](http://www.freightroute.co.uk/about-us/our-work-))
  * Warners Midlands PLC ([Privacy Policy](http://www.warners.co.uk/privacy-policy/))

 **11.    ****Data Controller**

  * The data controller of this website is: Jackson’s Art Supplies Limited, a UK Private Limited.
  * Company Number: 3913002
  * Registered Office: 1 Farleigh Place, London, N16 7SX
  * Operating Office: Unit J, Edison Close, Waterwells Business Park, Quedgeley, Gloucester, GL2 2FN

 **12.    ****Our Commitment to Data Security:**

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

Our website is hosted on its own secure server which is scanned continuously for malicious software by security software called ‘Comodo’

Though we have these procedures in place we can’t be held responsible for any intercepted information shared through our Site without our knowledge or permission.

 **Credit Card Security**

When placing an order and at the point that you click on the ‘Confirm Order’ button in order to pay, you will be taken to the PayPal website and you will see that the URL address has changed from Jacksonsart.com to https://securepayments.paypal.com/. You are now on the PayPal website and your card details are entered here, once completed and authorised by your bank, PayPal send you back to Jackson’s whilst advising us that your payment has gone through and that we may continue processing your order. At no point are your card details entered on the Jackson’s website nor can any member of the Jackson’s staff see or retrieve your card details. If at any point a refund is needed we advise PayPal and they apply the refund to your card.

 **13.    ****Our Commitment to Children's Privacy:**

Protecting the privacy of the young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 16, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 16.

 **14.    ****How You Can Access Your Information:**

You can request a copy of the data we have collected from you (order history, personal details…) by submitting an email request to our Data Protection Officer at [stuart@jacksonsart.co.uk](mailto:stuart@jacksonsart.co.uk). We will then be committed to emailing you a PDF detailing the data.

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

 **15.    ****How to Contact Us:**

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please call our Data Protection Officer at 01452 228482 619001 or send an email to stuart@jacksonsart.co.uk

In the extremely unlikely event that you are dissatisfied with any way that we handle your data requests, you are able to raise your issue with the ICO.

 **16.    ****Data Retention**

The Company shall not keep personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the purpose or purposes for which that personal data was originally collected, held, and processed.

When personal data is no longer required, all reasonable steps will be taken to erase or otherwise dispose of it without delay.

For full details of the Company’s approach to data retention, including retention periods for specific personal data types held by the Company, please refer to our Data Retention Policy.

 **17.    ****Your Rights**

Your rights under data protection laws include the right to access, erase, correct, restrict, and/or object to our use and processing of your personal data, as well as the right to portability of the data. 

You have the right to confirmation as to how and where we process your data. To the extent that the legal basis for our processing consents, you have the right to withdraw at any time.

If you consider our processing to infringe data protection laws, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.

 **18.    ****Changes to Our Privacy Policy:**

This privacy policy may change from time to time in line with legislation or industry developments. We will not explicitly inform our clients or website users of these changes. Instead, we recommend that you check this page occasionally for any policy changes. Specific policy changes and updates are mentioned in the change log below.

 **Change Log:**

24/05/18 - Privacy policy revised
